<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<refentry version="5.0-subset Scilab" xml:id="gauss2sci" xml:lang="en"
          xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
          xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
          xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
          xmlns:ns4="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
          xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
          xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
     <pubdate>$LastChangedDate:08-Aug-2011$</pubdate>
   </info>
   <refnamediv>
       <refname>gauss2sci</refname>
               <refpurpose>Gauss to Scilab translation </refpurpose>
   </refnamediv>
 
        <refsynopsisdiv>
               <title>CALLING SEQUENCE</title>
               <synopsis>gauss2sci(filein,lib,verbose)</synopsis>
        </refsynopsisdiv>
 
        <refsection>
           <title>PARAMETERS</title>
           <variablelist>
           <varlistentry>
 
           <term>Input</term>
 
<listitem><para>*  <term> filein </term> =  a string, the name of a file collecting Gauss programs and scripts</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>*  <term> lib </term> =  a string, the name of the library where the files resulting from the translation are put</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>*  <term> verbose </term> =  a boolean, indicating whether the Gauss lines of codes are displayed as they are translated (optional: %f if not given)</para></listitem>
 
 
 
<listitem><para>&#160;</para></listitem>
 
           </varlistentry>
 
          <varlistentry>
 
          <term>Output</term>
 
<listitem><para>* Nothing: the result of the translation is splitted into numerous files, one that gathers the lines of code corresponding to a script and one file per Gauss procedure.</para></listitem>
 
          </varlistentry>
          </variablelist>
        </refsection>
 
        <refsection>
               <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
Performs a partial and imperfect, even if substantial, translation of a Gauss file collecting Gauss programs and scripts. The result of the translation is splitted into numerous files, one that gathers the lines of code corresponding to a script and one file per Gauss program, whose name is the program name, suffixed by .sci.
 
        </refsection>
 
        <refsection>
               <title>EXAMPLE</title>
              <programlisting role="example"><![CDATA[
 
gauss2sci('c:/qreg/qreg.src','c:/qreg.sci')
// Suppose that you have put in the library 'c:/qreg' the qreg.scr file
// taken from Thierry Roncalli qreg library (http://www.thierry-roncalli.com/).
// Then the translation results in a file qreg.sce which, in this case, gathers the comments
// put before each function to describe what it does; 5 files _qreg_solvelp1.sci, _qreg_solvelp.sci,
// localqreg.sci, qreg.sci and setqreg.sci that are the translation of the 5 procedures
// with the same name (less the suffix '.sci') that you can find in the file qreg.src.
 
               ]]></programlisting>
        </refsection>
 
        <refsection>
               <title>AUTHOR</title>
Eric Dubois 2011
        </refsection>
</refentry>
